(WIND HOWLING)
(GUN FIRING)
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
(COMPUTER) 'YOUR MOVE:
Bishop to knight four.
'MY MOVE: Knight to rook three.'
Poor baby,
you're starting to lose it, aren't ya?
(COMPUTER) 'YOUR MOVE:
King to rook one.
'MY MOVE: Rook to knight six.
'Checkmate. Checkmate.'
You cheating bitch.
(GUN FIRING)
- Childs, what's he doing?
- Circling the camp.
Who is he?
- Said "Norge" or something on the side.
- It's Norwegian.
(SPEAKING NORWEGIAN)
(GUN FIRING)
- George, are you okay?
- Yeah, yeah, I'm okay.
- Are you?
- Yeah.
What's going on there?
(CHILDS) Watch it.
(MAN) Get back.
Easy.
Easy, easy, easy. Yes.
(MAN COUGHING)
First goddamn week of winter.
(GROANING)
Oh, come on. Four stitches.
Barely grazed you.
What were they doing flying that low,
shooting at a dog, at us?
Stir-crazy. Cabin fever. Who knows?
U.S. Number 31, calling McMurdo.
Come in. Over.
Urgent. Come in. Over.
Great.
- Come on, come on.
- Nobody!
Nobody. Get a hold of somebody.
Get a hold of anybody.
We gotta report this mess.
Look, I haven't been able to reach shit
in two weeks.
I doubt if anybody's talked to anybody
on this entire continent,
and you want me to reach somebody!
Maybe we're at war with Norway.
I was wondering when the El Capitan
was gonna get a chance to use his popgun.
- How long have they been stationed there?
- It says here only eight weeks.
(GARRY) Well, that's not long enough
for guys to go bonkers.
Bullshit, bwana.
Five minutes is enough
to put a man over down here.
(PALMER) Damn straight.
I mean, look at Palmer.
He been the way he is since the first day.
How many in their party?
They started with 10.
There'd be eight others left.
How do we know? Guys as crazy as that
could have done a lot of damage
to their own before they got to us.
- Nothing we can do about that.
- Yes, there is. I wanna go up.
- In this weather?
- Bennings?
Winds are gonna let up a tad
next couple of hours.
A tad?
Can't condone it much myself,
but it is a short haul.
An hour there, an hour back.
Shit, Doc, I'll give you the lift. No problem.
- (GARRY) Forget it, Palmer.
- Hey, thanks for thinking about it though.
Loaded with kerosene. I count 15 cans.
MacReady! Mac, get your gear on!
- Mac, it may not clear up for a week.
- Yeah.
- We're the closest ones to them.
- It's all right by me, Doc.
I'm just letting you know
we're taking a chance.
Quit the griping, MacReady.
Those clouds keep moving over the sun,
we're gonna get a whiteout.
We get caught in that,
you can scratch one doctor and one pilot.
This is real thin.
It'll clear as soon as you get up.
It's up to you, Mac.
If you don't wanna fly, we don't fly.
You really wanna save
those crazy Swedes, huh?
(DOC) Norwegians.
- Which way, Doc?
- Southwest.
You're gonna have to read the map.
'Cause I'm gonna be busy.
(ENGINE WHINING)
Mac's really taking it up, huh?
He knows what he's doing.
(♪ STEVIE WONDER: "SUPERSTITIOUS")
Nauls, will you turn that crap down?
I'm trying to get some sleep.
I was shot today.
Read, bwana. Will do.
♪ Writing's on the wall
♪ Very superstitious ♪
Anybody there?
Hey, Sweden!
They're not Swedish, Mac.
They're Norwegian.
Mac!
My God. What the hell happened here?
Come on, Doc.
(SIGHING)
- Portable video unit. Anything?
- It's all in Norwegian.
What are you doing, Doc?
Could be important work.
I wanna take it back with us.
Well, it's getting late. Let's hurry it up.
I'll check out the last few rooms.
Hey, Copper, come here!
Maybe they found a fossil,
the remains of some animal buried
in the ice, and they chopped it out.
- But where is it?
- Look at this.
(DOC) What is that?
Is that a man in there or something?
Whatever it is, they burned it up in a hurry.
Help me find a shovel, Doc.
We found this.
Jesus Christ.
(COUGHING)
(DOC) Blair, I'd like you to start
an autopsy right away.
(LOUD STATIC)
Did you reach anybody yet?
Reach anybody?
We're a thousand miles from nowhere, man,
and it's gonna get worse
before it gets better.
Well, stick to it, Windows. Stick to it.
Nothing wrong with this Norwegian,
physiologically anyway.
No drugs, no alcohol. Nothing.
Well, what we got here
is what appears to be, anyway,
a normal set of internal organs.
Heart,
lungs, kidneys, liver.
Intestines.
Seem to be normal.
(MAN ON TV) 'One, door number two
and door number three.
'And I think that Dawn Screen here
has got the one to trade in the most.
'I went to you first.
You brought your friend Anna.
'You've been consulting Anna all
through the show anyhow.
'You may as well consult her
one more time.'
I know how this one ends.
(♪ SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(♪ BILLIE HOLIDAY: "DON'T EXPLAIN")
(YELPS)
Clark, will you put this mutt with
the others where it belongs?
Yeah, okay.
Go ahead.
Go ahead. What are you waiting for?
(ALL BARKING)
(DOG WHIMPERING)
(DOG YELPS)
(CREATURE SCREECHES)
(DOG HOWLING)
(ALARM BLARING)
I don't know what the hell's in there,
but it's weird and pissed off, whatever it is.
Bennings, go get Childs.
What is this? What's going on?
- Hey, Palmer, what is this?
- I don't know.
- Childs, Mac wants the flamethrower!
- Mac wants the what?
- That's what he said. Now, move!
- Damn it.
(DOGS BARKING)
- Stay back.
- Hey, Mac, what is it?
(HIGH PITCHED SCREECH)
(HOWLING)
- Don't! No!
- Get away!
Get back! Get back!
(SQUEAKING)
Get your ass over here!
Burn it.
(GROWLING)
Damn it, Childs. Torch it!
(SHRIEKING)
Oh, my God.
Oh!
Look. Son of a bitch. Oh.
You see, what we're talking about here
is an organism
that imitates other life-forms,
and it imitates them perfectly.
When this thing attacked our dogs,
it tried to digest them,
absorb them,
and in the process,
shape its own cells to imitate them.
This, for instance. That's not dog.
It's imitation.
We got to it before it had time to finish.
Finish what?
Finish imitating these dogs.
(CLARK) Easy, easy. Good.
Easy, easy.
- Clark.
- Yeah?
Did you notice anything strange
about the dog, anything at all?
Strange? No.
What was the dog doing in the rec room?
I don't know.
He was just wandering around camp all day.
Are you saying to me the dog wasn't put
in the kennel until last night?
Right.
How long were you alone with that dog?
I don't know. An hour.
Hour and a half, maybe.
What the hell you looking at me
like that for?
- I don't know.
- What?
I don't know. It's probably nothing.
It's nothing at all.
How much more of this crap is there?
I don't know.
About nine hours, I'd say.
- We can't learn anything from this.
- (DOC) Guess not.
(GARRY) Where'd they take these shots?
Seems like they were spending
a lot of their time
in a little place northeast of their camp
about five or six miles.
(GARRY) What's that?
(MACREADY) It looks like something
buried under the ice.
(NORRIS) And look at that.
They're planting thermite charges.
(GARRY) Whatever it was, it was bigger
than that block of ice you found.
Here. This is it. The place where
they were spending most of their time.
- Pretty nasty out, Mac. 35 knots.
- Screw it. I'm gonna go up anyway.
Half a mile due east.
Jesus, how long do you figure
this has been in the ice?
Well, the backscatter effect's been
bringing things up
from way down around here for a long time.
I'd say... I'd say the ice it's buried in is
100,000 years old, at least.
- And those Norwegians blew it up?
- Yeah.
I don't know.
Thousands of years ago, it crashes,
and this thing...
gets thrown out or crawls out,
and it ends up freezing in the ice.
I just cannot believe
any of this voodoo bullshit.
Childs, it happens all the time, man.
They're falling out of the skies like flies.
(PALMER) Government knows
all about it. Right, Mac?
Do you believe
any of this voodoo bullshit, Blair?
Childs. Childs. Chariots Of The Gods, man.
They practically own South America.
I mean, they taught the Incas
everything they know.
So, come on, now, MacReady.
The Norwegians get a hold of this,
and they dig it up out of the ice.
Yes, Garry, they dig it up. They cart it back.
It gets thawed out, wakes up,
probably not in the best of moods.
- I don't know. I wasn't there.
- Which one of you disrespectful men
been tossing his dirty drawers
in the kitchen trash can, huh?
From now on
I want my kitchen clean, germfree.
Now how's this motherfucker wake up
after thousands of years in the ice?
- And how could it look like a dog?
- I don't know how.
'Cause it's different than us, see?
'Cause it's from outer space.
What do you want from me? Ask him.
You buy any of this, Blair?
(DOC ON PA) 'Mac, removing those things
out of the lab into the storeroom.
'Can you come get your stuff?'
Be there in a minute, Doc.
Through the door.
Right over here. Right over...
Sorry, Mac. You have to move your stuff...
Doc says we gotta lock him up.
Stash him in here and lock him up.
- I have to talk to you.
- I'm tired of talking, Fuchs.
I just wanna get up to my shack
and get drunk.
- Mac, it's important.
- What is it?
- Outside.
- It's 40 below outside.
In the Thiokol. Please, Mac.
- We ought to just burn these things.
- Can't burn the find of the century.
That's gonna win somebody the Nobel Prize.
You got the keys?
Get them from Garry.
I wanna get some stuff out of here.
There's something wrong with Blair.
He's locked himself in his room,
and he won't answer the door.
So I took one of his notebooks from the lab.
- Yeah?
- Listen.
"It could have imitated
a million life-forms on a million planets.
"Could change into any one of them
at any time.
"Now it wants life-forms on Earth."
It's getting cold in here,
and I haven't slept in days.
Wait a minute, Mac
Wait a minute.
"It needs to be alone and in close proximity
with a life-form to be absorbed.
"The chameleon strikes in the dark."
- So is Blair cracking up, or what?
- Damn it, MacReady.
"There is still cellular activity
in these burned remains.
"They're not dead yet."
Let's go, Bennings. I gotta get some sleep.
(RUSTLING)
Holy shit.
(KEYS CLATTERING)
Go get the doc.
I'll get Garry. We'll meet in Blair's room.
It's Bennings!
Bennings was right there.
Mac, I swear to God. It had a hold of him.
(ALARM BLARING)
Windows! Windows! Keep away from him!
Get back! Stay back!
It isn't Bennings.
(SCREECHING)
- My God, what was happening to him?
- If it had more time to finish
it would have looked,
sounded and acted just like Bennings.
I don't know what you're saying.
That was one of those things out there
trying to imitate him, Garry.
- Come on.
- MacReady, I know Bennings.
I've known him for 10 years. He's my friend.
We've gotta burn the rest of them.
All right, step back.
You sure that's all of them?
We cleaned out the storehouse, the lab.
There is nothing left.
Where's Blair?
I can't find Blair.
Where's everybody else?
Windows is in the radio room
still trying to get through.
Everyone else is in the rec room.
Well, you go on. I'll be in in a minute.
(CLATTERING)
Blair?
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
(GUN FIRING)
(BLAIR CHATTERING INCOHERENTLY)
(CLANGING)
(BLAIR) Don't! You son of a bitch.
You understand me?
- He's got a gun. Get back.
- Anybody interferes, I'll kill them.
- Jesus.
- Just leave it here. We're gonna talk.
He smashed up some of the chopper
pretty good.
Nobody talk to nobody!
Childs, go see if he got to the tractor.
Nobody gets in and out of here. Nobody.
You guys think I'm crazy. Well, that's fine.
Most of you don't know what's going on
around here.
Well, I'm damn well sure some of you do.
Christ.
He got most of the chopper and the tractor,
and he's killed the rest of the dogs.
Garry, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Now, Childs, go around to
the map room door. Talk to him.
Okay.
Norris, get a table from the lab.
Do you think that thing
wanted to be an animal?
No dogs make it a thousand miles
through the cold.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Nah, you don't understand!
That thing wanted to be us.
If the cell gets out
it could imitate everything
on the face of the earth
- and it's not gonna stop!
- Okay, Blair.
Come on, man,
you don't wanna hurt anybody.
I'll kill you.
(GRUNTS)
(PUNCHES LANDING)
(BLAIR GRUNTING)
Good shot, MacReady.
- Excuse me.
- Okay.
- All right, bring him up.
- Yeah.
Come on, Blair.
What about your shack?
I don't want him in my shack.
We'll lock him in the toolshed.
- (BLAIR) Why am I in here?
- For your own protection, Blair.
How you doing, old boy?
I don't know who to trust.
I know what you mean, Blair.
Trust's a tough thing to come by these days.
Tell you what.
Why don't you just trust in the Lord?
- Watch Clark.
- What?
I said, watch Clark.
And watch him close. Do you hear me?
And now the radio's gone.
- And so are the choppers.
- We're completely cut off.
All we can do now is hole up
'til spring, wait for the rescue team.
No, we don't wait.
Somebody in this camp
ain't what he appears to be.
Right now that may be one or two of us.
By spring, it could be all of us.
So how do we know who's human?
If I was an imitation, a perfect imitation,
how would you know if it was really me?
Is there some kind of test, Doc?
Well, yeah, possibly.
I've been thinking about a blood serum test.
(GARRY) What's that?
We could take a sample of each person's
blood, mix it with uncontaminated blood.
I suppose if there's a reaction,
we'd know who isn't human.
- We've got whole blood in storage.
- Start working on it.
Keep an eye on Clark.
He was close to that dog.
- Yeah.
Mac, we need Blair's help.
He's the only one who knows this organism.
He's too far gone.
But get the rest of his notebooks.
Start going through them.
Garry! Hey, you guys, come here!
- What?
- Somebody got to the blood.
What?
- Where's Clark?
- Right here.
- Wait a minute. Was this broken into?
- The lock is undamaged.
Somebody opened it, closed it,
then locked it.
Great.
Who's got access to it?
I guess I'm the only one.
And I got the only key.
- Would that test have worked, Doc?
- I think so, yes.
(NORRIS) Somebody else
sure as hell thought so.
Well, who else could've used that key?
Nobody! I just give it to Copper
whenever he needs it.
Could anybody have gotten it from you,
Doc?
I don't see how. As soon as I'm finished,
I return it right away.
Great.
- (FUCHS) When was the last time you used it?
- (DOC) Day or so ago, I guess.
I suppose somebody could have
lifted it off me...
Oh, come on!
That key ring of yours
is always hooked to your belt.
(BOTH YELLING)
Accusing everybody...
(MACREADY) Stop it! It ain't worth it!
Copper's the only one
who's got any business with it.
Now wait a minute, Garry!
You've been in here on several occasions.
Doc thought of the test.
(CHILDS) So what?
Is that supposed to clear him?
(BOTH YELLING)
Windows! Windows!
(PANTING)
Put that down!
- No.
- I'll put this right through your head.
You guys gonna listen to Garry?
You gonna let him give the orders?
He could be one of those things.
Windows.
Wait a minute. Just take it easy.
Put the gun down.
Put it down.
You don't want to hurt anybody.
Right.
(GARRY) On the floor.
It's on the floor.
I don't know about Copper,
but I give you my word,
I did not go near that blood.
But I guess you'll all feel a little easier
if somebody else was in charge.
Norris, I can't see anybody objecting to you.
I'm sorry, fellas, but I'm not up to it.
- I'll take it.
- Like hell you will.
It should be somebody
a little more even-tempered, Childs.
(MACREADY) All right.
(WIND HOWLING)
(MACREADY) I know I'm human.
And if you were all these things,
then you'd just attack me right now.
So some of you are still human.
This thing doesn't want to show itself.
It wants to hide inside an imitation.
It'll fight if it has to.
But it's vulnerable out in the open.
If it takes us over,
then it has no more enemies,
nobody left to kill it.
And then it's won.
There's a storm hitting us in six hours.
We're gonna find out who's who.
All right, Doc, Garry and Clark,
move over there away from the others.
Norris, you and Childs
shoot them up with morphine.
Tie them down in the rec room
and watch them.
Fuchs, you start working
on a new technique.
- I need Doc's help.
- You don't wanna drug me.
Mac, I'm not a prisoner!
Let me do it.
You're gonna break the needle in my arm.
No, Doc, he's doing a real fine job.
I'm gonna hide this tape when I'm finished.
If none of us make it,
at least there'll be some kind of record.
Storm's been hitting us hard now
for 48 hours.
We still have nothing to go on.
One other thing,
I think it rips through your clothes
when it takes you over.
Windows found some shredded long johns,
but the name tag was missing.
They could be anybody's.
Nobody...
Nobody trusts anybody now.
And we're all very tired.
(PLAYBACK) 'Nobody trusts
anybody now.'
There's nothing else I can do.
Just wait.
R.J. MacReady, helicopter pilot,
U.S. Outpost, number 31.
You come up with anything yet?
One or two ideas.
But, MacReady, I've been thinking.
If a small particle of this thing
is enough to take over an entire organism,
then everyone should prepare
their own meals.
And I suggest we only eat out of cans.
All right.
(CLATTERING)
Who's that?
Anybody see Fuchs?
Somebody blew out a fuse in the lab.
Lights were out for an hour.
Anyone of us could've gotten to him.
All right, we gotta find him.
Nauls, why don't you come with me
and we'll look outside.
Palmer, you and Windows check the inside.
I ain't going with Windows.
I ain't going with him. I'll go with Childs.
- Hey, fuck you, Palmer!
- I ain't going with you!
- Who says I want you going with me?
- Cut the bullshit!
Windows, you come with us.
Norris, you stay here.
Any of them move, you fry them.
You hear anything, cut loose on the sirens.
We all meet back here
in 20 minutes regardless.
And everybody watch whoever
you're with. Real close.
(WIND HOWLING)
Hey, Blair.
Blair, have you seen Fuchs?
I don't wanna stay out here anymore.
I wanna come back inside.
Funny things.
I hear funny things out here.
- Have you come across Fuchs?
- It ain't Fuchs.
It ain't Fuchs.
I'm not gonna harm anybody.
There's nothing wrong with me.
And if there was, I'm all better now.
I'd like to come back inside.
Now you've got my promise.
We'll see.
Wait a minute, man.
I wanna come back inside,
don't you understand?
I'm all right. I'm much better
and I won't harm anybody.
You gotta let me come back inside.
(WIND HOWLING)
Hold it!
Is it Fuchs?
Yeah.
Why would it burn him?
Flare. Maybe he tried to burn it.
Maybe he burned himself
before it could get to him.
Great! Now what are we gonna do?
You go inside.
Tell the others we found Fuchs.
We'll be in as soon as we can.
- Where are we going?
- Up to my shack.
What the hell for?
'Cause when I left yesterday,
I turned the lights off.
How long have they been out there?
Forty, 45 minutes.
We better start closing off
the outside doors.
Hey! All of you, come here!
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Open up! Open up this door! Open up!
Open up!
Close that door.
(PANTING)
Where's MacReady?
I cut him loose of the line up by his shack.
- Cut him loose?
- Yeah.
We were up checking around his place,
I found this.
Look. It was stashed in his oil furnace.
Wind must've dislodged it,
but I don't think he saw me find it.
I made sure I got ahead of him
on the towline on the way back.
I cut him loose.
- MacReady?
- He's one of them.
- When do you think it got to him?
- I don't know.
It could've been anytime, anywhere.
(CHILDS) If it did get to him.
Look, Childs, come on.
- When the lights went out.
- That would've been perfect.
Right. You said guys were missing.
Windows, where were you?
I told you to shut your mouth!
(ALL YELLING)
(NORRIS) This is just what it wants!
To pit us against each other.
- Let's open it.
- Hell no!
You think he's changed
into one of those things?
He's had plenty of time.
Nothing human could've made it back
here in this weather without a guide line.
- Let's open it now.
- Why are you so anxious to let him in here?
Because it's so close.
- May be our best chance to blow it away.
- (CHILDS) Let him freeze to death outside.
Childs, what if we're wrong about him?
Well, then, we're wrong!
(GLASS SHATTERING)
The supply window!
All right, all right, we got no choice now!
Damn it! He's got the keys!
(MACREADY) What's going on?
The towline snapped.
Bullshit, Childs.
He's got to know damn well I cut it!
You're a dead man, MacReady!
Or a dead whatever the hell you are!
Anyone messes with me
and the whole camp goes.
Come on, Childs, burn me.
Put those torches on the floor and back off.
Back off. Way off.
- You asshole.
- You'd have done the same thing.
Don't argue with him.
Where's the rest?
Come on, man, I mean it!
It's cool, MacReady, come on.
Yeah. Yeah, man, just relax.
Anybody touches me... and we go.
(GROANS)
- He's not breathing!
- Go untie the doc.
Get him in here. And bring the others.
From now on, nobody gets out of my sight.
Let me at him.
So, you sweethearts were about to have
a little lynching party, huh?
I might just have to put an end to you
on general principles, Nauls.
Did it ever occur to the jury that anybody
could've gotten some of my clothes
- and stuck them up the furnace?
- (CHILDS) We ain't buying that.
Quit that bickering over there!
Windows, wheel that defibrillator over here.
Give me those paddles!
(CHILDS) You're gonna have to
sleep sometime, MacReady.
I'm a real light sleeper, Childs.
If anyone tries to wake me...
Clear!
- Clear!
- Clear.
(SCREAMING)
- We're on fire, MacReady! We're on fire!
- Get back! Just wait!
All right, go!
Windows! Windows, get in here!
You gotta be fucking kidding.
(SCREECHING)
- What do you got in mind, MacReady?
- A little test.
And, Windows, you and Palmer,
tie everybody down real tight.
- What for?
- For your health.
Let's rush him!
He's not gonna blow us all up!
No, no, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Let's do what Mac says.
I mean,
he wasted Norris pretty quick, didn't he?
That's close enough, Clark.
He ain't tying me up.
Then I'll have to kill you, Childs.
Then kill me.
I mean it.
(GUN COCKING)
I guess you do.
(GUN FIRING)
Geez. This is bullshit, Mac!
- (MACREADY) Finish it, Palmer.
- They're dead, Mac!
- Windows?
- Yo?
You tie up Palmer over here.
(MACREADY) We're gonna draw
a little bit of everybody's blood
'cause we're gonna find out
who's the thing.
Watching Norris in there
gave me the idea that
maybe every part of him was a whole.
Every little piece was an individual animal
with a built-in desire to protect its own life.
You see, when a man bleeds,
it's just tissue.
The blood from one of you things
won't obey when it's attacked.
It'll try and survive.
Crawl away from a hot needle the same.
Now you.
That's good.
All right, move back, over there.
I guess you're okay.
All right. Put that on and watch them.
Now I'll show you what I already know.
It's a crock of shit.
Let's try the doc and Clark.
Now Clark.
Then Clark was human, huh?
Which makes you a murderer, don't it?
Palmer now.
This is pure nonsense.
It doesn't prove a thing.
I thought you'd feel that way, Garry.
You were the only one that could've
got to that blood.
We'll do you last.
(SCREECHES)
Get him away from me! MacReady, burn it!
(ALL YELLING)
What is it?
Come on!
Get me out of here!
Windows, blast him!
(CHILDS) Get me out of here!
Get me out of here!
(WINDOWS SCREAMING)
(ALL YELLING)
(SHATTERING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Windows!
(CHILDS) Get me out of here!
MacReady, get in here!
Come on, hurry up!
He's coming back! Burn it!
Burn it, for God's sake!
Hurry up, MacReady! Burn it!
Let's do it.
(CHILDS) Get me out of here! Cut me loose!
Cut me the hell... Come on, get me
out of here! Come on, get me out of here!
Cut me loose, damn it!
I know you gentlemen
have been through a lot,
but when you find the time,
I'd rather not spend the rest
of this winter tied to this fucking couch!
Childs.
We're going out to give Blair the test.
If he tries to make it back here
and we're not with him... burn him.
(WIND HOWLING)
Mac, the door's open!
How'd he get out?
The door was bolted from the outside.
(WOOD CREAKS)
(GARRY) Blair?
(NAULS) Hey, Blair, you down there?
We got something for ya!
(MACREADY) Blair's been busy out here
all by himself.
What is it?
Something he's been making.
It's a ship of some kind.
He stole the parts from the helicopter.
The smart S.O.B. put it together
piece by piece.
Where was he trying to go?
Anyplace but here.
Hey, you guys, come here. Come here.
I think I saw Childs outside
the main entrance of the camp.
- What's he doing outside?
- I don't know.
Got a flare?
He got back inside and blew the generator.
In six hours,
it'll be a hundred below in here.
Well, that's suicide!
Not for that thing. It wants to freeze now.
It's got no way out of here.
It just wants to go to sleep in the cold
until the rescue team finds it.
What can we do? What can we do?
Whether we make it or not,
we can't let that thing freeze again.
Maybe we'll just warm things up
a little around here.
We're not getting out of here alive.
But neither is that thing.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Generator room.
The generator's gone.
Any way we can fix it?
It's gone, MacReady.
All right.
We gotta bring this whole place
right down into the ice.
Garry, plant yours in the old storage room.
Nauls, down by the generator.
God!
(MOANING)
How's it coming in there?
I said, how's it...
(GROWLING)
Yeah, fuck you, too!
You the only one who made it?
Not the only one.
Did you kill it?
Where were you, Childs?
Thought I saw Blair.
I went out after him
and got lost in the storm.
Fire's got the temperature up
all over the camp.
Won't last long, though.
Neither will we.
How will we make it?
Maybe we shouldn't.
If you're worried about me...
If we've got any surprises for each other,
I don't think we're in much shape
to do anything about it.
Well... What do we do?
Why don't we just
wait here for a little while?
See what happens.